<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shivanshu Singh</title>
    <link>https://r4ndombits.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shivanshu Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 19:33:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://r4ndombits.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Past As Present: Review</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/past-as-present-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 19:33:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/past-as-present-review/</guid>
      <description>The implication of the past as present requires recognition of the integration of one with another, but also the distinctive difference in societies of earlier times and our times.
 Romilla Thapar discusses, in this book, how the past (many times imaginary) is invoked to give a force to a current political movement. She claims that history, especially ancient history, is not static, it changes as and when we develop a more in-depth understanding of archaeological evidence and their multidimensional understanding from the intersection of multiple disciples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malevolent Republic: Review</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/malevolent-republic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:36:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/malevolent-republic-review/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing natural or preordained about Indian unity. Indian civilization is antique; Indian unity is rare and recent.
 Malevolent republic is a terrifying and hard-hitting account of the political, social, and religious landscape of India, casting merciless eyes upon all prime ministers, from Nehru to Modi, with no corner left untouched. We do perceive pride as a legitimate emotion in the national context. This is the kind of book that would force us to recognize another side of the coin: shame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Year of Inactivity &amp; Procrastination</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/a-year-of-inactivity-and-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 02:21:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/a-year-of-inactivity-and-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>I have been meaning to write a post for a long time, but every time I was held down by some other activity, or so I thought. Procrastination is the bane of most inexperienced writers, and in my case, it also reflected in &amp;ldquo;my ways&amp;rdquo; of doing assignments and projects since last two years. I am not saying that procrastination is the only cause of my inactivity, but it does contribute to it a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 20:07:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>When a bookmark tumbles out of an old book pristine and unwrinkled, it is like a gasp of breath from another century.
&amp;ndash; Don Borchert
 This page contains the pointers to various blogs, podcasts and articles that I came across and find interesting. I am hoping that this will be a better and a more reliable way to keep track of all these resources.
Blogs &amp;amp; Articles  What Color is Your Function?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 19:35:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/books/</guid>
      <description>Reading is dreaming with open eyes.
&amp;ndash; Yoyo
   Favorites The Free Voice: On Democracy, Culture and the Nation   Shoe Dog: A Memoir by the Creator of NIKE   Before We Were Yours   The Sense of an Ending   And the Mountains Echoed   The Nightingale   The Book Thief   Guns, Germs, and Steel: The Fates of Human Societies   When Breath Becomes Air   The Fountainhead   A Thousand Splendid Suns   Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind   1984   The Selfish Gene   The God Delusion    Currently Reading University of Berkshire Hathaway: 30 Years of Lessons Learned from Warren Buffett &amp;amp; Charlie Munger at the Annual Shareholders Meeting   Nationalism   The Past As Present: Forging Contemporary Identities Through History   The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business    Read The Brain: The Story of You   Malevolent Republic: A Short History of New India   Notes from Underground   Working: Researching, Interviewing, Writing   Ghachar Ghochar   In Service of the Republic: The Art and Science of Economic Policy   Liar&amp;#39;s Poker   The Big Short: Inside the Doomsday Machine   The Warren Buffett Way: Investment Strategies of the World&amp;#39;s Greatest Investor   Flash Boys: A Wall Street Revolt   That Which Is Seen and That Which Is Not Seen   A Random Walk Down Wall Street: The Time-Tested Strategy for Successful Investing   My Seditious Heart: Collected Nonfiction   Raavan: Enemy of Aryavarta (Ram Chandra #3)   The Three Languages of Politics   India&amp;#39;s Greatest Speeches   The Free Voice: On Democracy, Culture and the Nation   The Metamorphosis   The Third Pillar: How Markets and the State Leave the Community Behind   Breakfast at Tiffany&amp;#39;s and Three Stories   IIM Ahmedabad Business Books: Day to Day Economics   Yuganta: The End of an Epoch   Nikola Tesla: Imagination and the Man That Invented the 20th Century   Currency Wars: The Making of the Next Global Crisis   The Last Lecture   The Google Story: Inside the Hottest Business, Media, and Technology Success of Our Time   I Do What I Do   My Inventions   Shoe Dog: A Memoir by the Creator of NIKE   The Art of UNIX Programming   Hackers &amp;amp; Painters: Big Ideas from the Computer Age   Losing My Virginity: How I&amp;#39;ve Survived, Had Fun, and Made a Fortune Doing Business My Way   It Ends with Us   To the Lighthouse   The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master   Introduction to Computation and Programming Using Python   The Code Book: The Science of Secrecy from Ancient Egypt to Quantum Cryptography   Before We Were Yours   Gandhi: An autobiography   The Zahir   The Opposite of Loneliness: Essays and Stories   The Intelligent Investor   The Importance of Being Earnest   The Dark Net: Inside the Digital Underworld   Siddhartha   The Little Prince   Scion of Ikshvaku (Ram Chandra #1)   The Sense of an Ending   A Man Called Ove   Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World   Sita: Warrior of Mithila (Ram Chandra #2)   The Hobbit, or There and Back Again   The Return of the King (The Lord of the Rings, #3)   The Two Towers (The Lord of the Rings, #2)   The Fellowship of the Ring (The Lord of the Rings, #1)   Origin (Robert Langdon, #5)   The Oath of the Vayuputras (Shiva Trilogy, #3)   The Secret of the Nagas (Shiva Trilogy #2)   Deception Point   Harry Potter and the Cursed Child: Parts One and Two (Harry Potter, #8)   Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows (Harry Potter, #7)   Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince (Harry Potter, #6)   Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire (Harry Potter, #4)   Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix (Harry Potter, #5)   Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (Harry Potter, #3)   Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets (Harry Potter, #2)   And the Mountains Echoed   The Immortals of Meluha (Shiva Trilogy, #1)   Harry Potter and the Sorcerer&amp;#39;s Stone (Harry Potter, #1)   Digital Fortress   The Lost Symbol (Robert Langdon, #3)   Wonder (Wonder, #1)   The Perks of Being a Wallflower   And Then There Were None   Rich Dad, Poor Dad   The Catcher in the Rye   To Kill a Mockingbird   A Tale of Two Cities   The Nightingale   Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future   The Monk Who Sold His Ferrari: A Fable About Fulfilling Your Dreams and Reaching Your Destiny   Pride and Prejudice   The Time Machine   The Moral Animal: Why We Are the Way We Are - The New Science of Evolutionary Psychology   The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck: A Counterintuitive Approach to Living a Good Life   Thirteen Reasons Why   What If?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for highly disposable development environments</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/docker-for-highly-disposable-dev-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 08:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/docker-for-highly-disposable-dev-environments/</guid>
      <description>Virtual machines are the perfect way of isolating your work environment from your host environment. But when your work is only limited to the user-space programs, this perfect isolation, which comes at the price of performance, is not required.
With the onset of namespaces in linux kernel, the concept of containers (sometimes called lightVM) came to light. Unlike jails, namespaces also isolate and visualize the process&amp;rsquo;s pids, uids, IPC and network access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Harry Potter</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/lessons-from-harry-potter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 08:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/lessons-from-harry-potter/</guid>
      <description>Harry Potter(HP) series, one of the most celebrated set of books of all times, always have more to see than meets the eye. Apart from spectacular fantasy world, brilliant writing and interesting plot, you will observe many latent moral lessons. Here&amp;rsquo;re some:
 You are not defined by your illness  Remus Lupin, a werewolf, did not go to exile like other werewolves. Instead, he conceals his illness and leads a normal life by preparing for full moon days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey from Windows to Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/journey-from-windows-to-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 08:43:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/journey-from-windows-to-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Windows, the most popular operating system, works well for the day-to-day activities but is of little help when it comes to programming and development.
Inspired by seniors, I took my first step towards using Ubuntu, the most popular linux, as my host operating system about a year ago. It felt very uncomfortable at first to use this not-so-good-looking OS. But overtime, the simplicity and the ease of use overshadowed the unsightly UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/about/</guid>
      <description>It is our choices, that show what we truly are, far more than our abilities.
&amp;ndash; J.K. Rowling, Harry Potter
 I am Shivanshu Singh, a graduate with a double major in Computer Science Engineering &amp;amp; Mechanical Engineering from Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, currently working in a high-frequency trading firm.
Here, you will find posts about books, interesting tech stuff, computer languages, operating systems, networks.. In short, from my reflections on random topics to articles on science, everything that matters to me will be posted here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>