<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shivanshu Singh</title>
    <link>https://shivnshu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shivanshu Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 20:07:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shivnshu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://shivnshu.github.io/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 20:07:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivnshu.github.io/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>When a bookmark tumbles out of an old book pristine and unwrinkled, it is like a gasp of breath from another century.
&amp;ndash; Don Borchert
 This page contains the pointers to various blogs, podcasts and articles that I came across and find interesting. I am hoping that this will be a better and a more reliable way to keep track of all these resources.
Blogs &amp;amp; Articles  What Color is Your Function?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://shivnshu.github.io/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 19:35:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivnshu.github.io/books/</guid>
      <description>  Reading is dreaming with open eyes.
&amp;ndash; Yoyo
 
Favorites                Currently Reading      Read                      $(&#39;.mygallery&#39;).justifiedGallery({ rowHeight : 200, lastRow : &#39;nojustify&#39;, margins : 7, randomize: true });  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for highly disposable development environments</title>
      <link>https://shivnshu.github.io/posts/docker-for-highly-disposable-dev-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 08:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivnshu.github.io/posts/docker-for-highly-disposable-dev-environments/</guid>
      <description>Virtual machines are the perfect way of isolating your work environment from your host environment. But when your work is only limited to the user-space programs, this perfect isolation, which comes at the price of performance, is not required.
With the onset of namespaces in linux kernel, the concept of containers (sometimes called lightVM) came to light. Unlike jails, namespaces also isolate and visualize the process&amp;rsquo;s pids, uids, IPC and network access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey from Windows to Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://shivnshu.github.io/posts/journey-from-windows-to-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 08:43:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivnshu.github.io/posts/journey-from-windows-to-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Windows, the most popular operating system, works well for the day-to-day activities but is of little help when it comes to programming and development.
Inspired by seniors, I took my first step towards using Ubuntu, the most popular linux, as my host operating system about a year ago. It felt very uncomfortable at first to use this not-so-good-looking OS. But overtime, the simplicity and the ease of use overshadowed the unsightly UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://shivnshu.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shivnshu.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>It is our choices, that show what we truly are, far more than our abilities.
&amp;ndash; J.K. Rowling, Harry Potter
 I am Shivanshu Singh, a fifth-year undergraduate majoring in Computer Science Engineering &amp;amp; Mechanical Engineering at Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur.
Here, you will find posts about books, interesting tech stuff, computer languages, operating systems, networks.. In short, from my reflections on random topics to articles on science, everything that matters to me will be posted here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>