<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shivanshu Singh</title>
    <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shivanshu Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:36:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://r4ndombits.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Malevolent Republic: Review</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/malevolent-republic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 11:36:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/malevolent-republic-review/</guid>
      <description>There’s nothing natural or preordained about Indian unity. Indian civilization is antique; Indian unity is rare and recent.
 Malevolent republic is a terrifying and hard-hitting account of the political, social, and religious landscape of India, casting merciless eyes upon all prime ministers, from Nehru to Modi, with no corner left untouched. We do perceive pride as a legitimate emotion in the national context. This is the kind of book that would force us to recognize another side of the coin: shame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Year of Inactivity &amp; Procrastination</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/a-year-of-inactivity-and-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 02:21:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/a-year-of-inactivity-and-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>I have been meaning to write a post for a long time, but every time I was held down by some other activity, or so I thought. Procrastination is the bane of most inexperienced writers, and in my case, it also reflected in &amp;ldquo;my ways&amp;rdquo; of doing assignments and projects since last two years. I am not saying that procrastination is the only cause of my inactivity, but it does contribute to it a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for highly disposable development environments</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/docker-for-highly-disposable-dev-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 08:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/docker-for-highly-disposable-dev-environments/</guid>
      <description>Virtual machines are the perfect way of isolating your work environment from your host environment. But when your work is only limited to the user-space programs, this perfect isolation, which comes at the price of performance, is not required.
With the onset of namespaces in linux kernel, the concept of containers (sometimes called lightVM) came to light. Unlike jails, namespaces also isolate and visualize the process&amp;rsquo;s pids, uids, IPC and network access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from Harry Potter</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/lessons-from-harry-potter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 08:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/lessons-from-harry-potter/</guid>
      <description>Harry Potter(HP) series, one of the most celebrated set of books of all times, always have more to see than meets the eye. Apart from spectacular fantasy world, brilliant writing and interesting plot, you will observe many latent moral lessons. Here&amp;rsquo;re some:
 You are not defined by your illness  Remus Lupin, a werewolf, did not go to exile like other werewolves. Instead, he conceals his illness and leads a normal life by preparing for full moon days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey from Windows to Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/journey-from-windows-to-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 08:43:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://r4ndombits.com/posts/journey-from-windows-to-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Windows, the most popular operating system, works well for the day-to-day activities but is of little help when it comes to programming and development.
Inspired by seniors, I took my first step towards using Ubuntu, the most popular linux, as my host operating system about a year ago. It felt very uncomfortable at first to use this not-so-good-looking OS. But overtime, the simplicity and the ease of use overshadowed the unsightly UI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>